Aladdin Company Records Collection 1907-1989 (bulk 1940-1982)
Clarke Historical Library
- Aladdin Company Collection - Series #10, (Books and Magazines)
  - Records, Photographs and Films (Videotapes (6 VHS, 3 Beta) of 9 Reels of Construction Film. See summary of film contents by Matyn, Dec. 2005) - Argosy. Aladdin article, pp. 6f., adv. P.31. July, 1972,1972 (Box 252, Folder 3041)
  - Records, Photographs and Films (Videotapes (6 VHS, 3 Beta) of 9 Reels of Construction Film. See summary of film contents by Matyn, Dec. 2005) - Sears, Robebuck Millwork Catalog. n.d. (c. 1922),1922 (Box 252, Folder 3042)
  - Records, Photographs and Films (Videotapes (6 VHS, 3 Beta) of 9 Reels of Construction Film. See summary of film contents by Matyn, Dec. 2005) - Low Cost Homes. Bay City, MI: Aladdin Co., n.d. Copyright by National Plan Service Inc., n.d.,undated (Box 252, Folder 3043)
  - Records, Photographs and Films (Videotapes (6 VHS, 3 Beta) of 9 Reels of Construction Film. See summary of film contents by Matyn, Dec. 2005) - Commerce Magazine. Prefabricated housing. Feb. 1946,1946 (Box 252, Folder 3044)
  - Records, Photographs and Films (Videotapes (6 VHS, 3 Beta) of 9 Reels of Construction Film. See summary of film contents by Matyn, Dec. 2005) - The Complete Book of Prefabs, Kits and Manufactured Houses. N.Y.: Faucett Columbine, 1981. Aladdin Co. on p. 140,1981 (Box 252, Folder 3045)
- Aladdin Company Collection - MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS
  - Box of miscellaneous unsorted papers,undated (Box 253, Folder 3046)
  - Box of miscellaneous unsorted papers,undated (Box 254, Folder 3047)
  - Construction standardization book #3,undated (Box 255, Folder 3048)
  - Construction standardization book #2,undated (Box 255, Folder 3049)
  - Sales. Pricing. Millwork Pricing Basis, 1922. Sales Office Reports, 1922,1922 (Box 255, Folder 3050)
  - Consecutive house order shipping list. 1954-1981,1954-1981 (Box 255, Folder 3051)
  - Construction standardization book #1 “Checked complete 2-4-22”, keep “Bay City Office:”,1922 (Box 255, Folder 3052)
  - Old Profit & Loss Statement Forms,undated (Box 255, Folder 3053)
  - envelope: Annual Report of Unclaimed or Abandoned Property forms,undated (Box 255, Folder 3054)
  - envelope: Garnishments,undated (Box 255, Folder 3055)
  - envelope: old auto & truck data,undated (Box 255, Folder 3056)
  - envelope: auto & truck data,undated (Box 255, Folder 3057)
  - envelope: personal property statements – city assessor's reports,undated (Box 255, Folder 3058)
  - envelope: unclaimed property reports to State of Minnesota,undated (Box 255, Folder 3059)
  - envelope: city fire inspection 4/8/1968, A.D.T. 9/21/82,1968-1982 (Box 255, Folder 3060)
  - envelope: Window order work sheets,undated (Box 255, Folder 3061)
  - envelope: tax statement 1985 unpaid,1985 (Box 255, Folder 3062)
  - Bank Book – Aladdin Co., 012-0016-1, general account, PNB (People's National Bank & Trust Co.),undated (Box 255, Folder 3063)
  - Bank Book – Aladdin Co., 012-0017-9, payroll, PNB (People's National Bank & Trust Co.),undated (Box 255, Folder 3064)
  - Bank Book – Aladdin Co., 012-0017-9, payroll, PNB (People's National Bank & Trust Co.) - now New Century Bank,undated (Box 255, Folder 3065)
  - Bank Book – Aladdin Co., 012-0017-9, payroll, PNB (People's National Bank & Trust Co.) - now New Century Bank 10/5/79 – 7/23/85,1979-1985 (Box 255, Folder 3066)
  - Packet of materials,undated (Box 255, Folder 3067)
  - A.D.T. Central Station Service – U.S. House of Representatives committee on state taxation of interstate commerce - valuation, Aladdin capitol stock, May 1954,1954 (Box 255, Folder 3067a)
  - Consumers Power Co.,undated (Box 255, Folder 3067b)
  - I.B.M. automatic electric typewriter – maintenance agreement – canceled 8/24/78,1978 (Box 255, Folder 3067c)
  - Merillet Woodworking Co. contract,undated (Box 255, Folder 3067d)
  - Standard Oil Co.,undated (Box 255, Folder 3067e)
  - Stanley Alarm System Agreement,undated (Box 255, Folder 3067f)
  - Report: United States House of Representatives committee on judiciary on state taxation of interstate commerce,undated (Box 255, Folder 3067g)
  - SA Lambert's letter re. Agencies use tax,undated (Box 255, Folder 3067h)
  - Changes in assessments, personal property, exchange of accident identification info., Lumber/etc. resold by Jim White Lumber Sales in 1982, documents concerning Aladdin Mill property – 1985, Downtown Development Plan, accounting – hiring information for Theresa Roznowski, Aladdin vehicle tax info., 1985 sales/use/withholding tax returns,1982-1985, undated (Box 255, Folder 3068)
  - Insurance information,undated (Box 255, Folder 3069)
  - Aladdin Co. Special Account, 012-0018-7,undated (Box 255, Folder 3070)
  - Bank Statements – payroll,undated (Box 255, Folder 3071)
  - envelope: bank statements,undated (Box 255, Folder 3072)
  - Misc. documents,undated (Box 255, Folder 3073)
  - Bank book, 012-0016-1, general account, 1985-1988,1958-1988 (Box 255, Folder 3074)
  - Selection of Federal Tax Deposit Coupon Books #1-4, “All used up for period 1/30/84 thru 6/25/85,1984-1985 (Box 255, Folder 3075)
  - Payroll forms – payment checks,undated (Box 255, Folder 3076)
  - Misc. tax documents, 1984-1986,1984-1986 (Box 255, Folder 3077)
  - Box of miscellaneous unsorted papers,undated (Box 256, Folder 3078)
  - Box of miscellaneous unsorted papers,undated (Box 257, Folder 3079)
  - Box of miscellaneous unsorted papers,undated (Box 258, Folder 3080)
  - Records, Box of miscellaneous unsorted papers,undated (Box 259, Folder 3081)